<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nikolai Kim</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/</link><description>Recent content on Nikolai Kim</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>CC0-1.0</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 21:13:56 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nikolai.kim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog Migraiton</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/blog-migraiton/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 21:13:56 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/blog-migraiton/</guid><description>&lt;p>I decided to move my weblog from Micro.blog to a self-hosted static website. While I enjoy the platform, I don&amp;rsquo;t really use anything but a custom domain feature.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clean Slate</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/clean-slate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 09:52:47 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/clean-slate/</guid><description>Over time, I created and abandoned many repositories on GitHub. Removing them completely is an involved process, though. They really want to make sure you are intentional and know the consequences.
Of course, this is great, but not when you need to delete a dozen of projects. That&amp;rsquo;s 6 times more clicks!
Here is the solution I came up with — https://clean-slate.surge.sh It allows selecting multiple repositories and deleting them without confirmations.</description></item><item><title>Monthly Subscription</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/monthly-subscription/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 21:26:21 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/monthly-subscription/</guid><description>Every time my sends a payment notification, I remember I have a blog. Does this happen to anyone else? 😅</description></item><item><title>Recap</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 10:31:14 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/recap/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since the fucking war started, I was unable to pay for and publish on Micro.blog. I tried Publii as an alternative, but unfortunately, it is not that convenient.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>March 3, 2022</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/march-3-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 20:01:57 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/march-3-2022/</guid><description>Honestly, I never thought I’ll be preparing for fleeing from my home and country one day. Now that Russia is nearly declaring a state of war, instead of a “special military operation” it becomes a top priority to make sure my family is safe 🙏</description></item><item><title>Monochrome</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/monochrome/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 23:34:50 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/monochrome/</guid><description>I recall someone said that monochrome picture is less attractive for human eye. Why don’t I try reducing screen time by switching my phone to black and white? My first 30 day experiment has now begun… 🧑‍🔬</description></item><item><title>Address Books Are Still an Option</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/address-books-are-still-an-option/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:30:21 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/address-books-are-still-an-option/</guid><description>&lt;p>I used to consider contact management tools something insignificant. Why spend time meticulously updating information about people when it is displayed on their IM profiles?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, it is… until the service goes down.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>IELTS Reading Life Hack</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/ielts-reading-life-hack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 01:39:30 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/ielts-reading-life-hack/</guid><description>I’ve been into IELTS for the last week. While doing some reading with the latest preparation materials from Cambridge Press, I found highlighting relevant parts the most helpful strategy for me. It becomes easier to navigate a text with every other highlighted piece. As the result, I make 1-2 mistakes instead of 4-6 without it. I was lucky to find an application of Pareto principle to my work here.</description></item><item><title>Mock Ielts Results</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/mock-ielts-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 03:40:02 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/mock-ielts-results/</guid><description>Well, the results came in, 7.5-6-7-7 🙂 To be honest, I’m pretty happy because I just went for it without any preparation. Now the plan is to fix Reading and make other “lucky” 7s more “confident”.</description></item><item><title>Mock IELTS</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/mock-ielts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 02:43:52 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/mock-ielts/</guid><description>Today I took a mock IELTS. It looks like I will need at least 6.5 for all sections except Listening, which should be 7.5. The results should come in 48 hours, so now I’m just waiting 😴</description></item><item><title>Good Morning</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/good-morning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 12:12:51 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/good-morning/</guid><description>It looks even more hazy in person
Photograph of a cityscape from the 15th floor</description></item><item><title>Therapist Tomorrow</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/therapist-tomorrow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 01:58:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/therapist-tomorrow/</guid><description>I’m looking forward to talking to my therapist tomorrow. So far, it has not been a walk in the park, but I know the process is rewarding, so… Is there any better time to heal some wounds than now? 😇</description></item><item><title>One Typed Page</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/one-typed-page/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 23:50:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/one-typed-page/</guid><description>A web project where everyone can publish a photograph of their type 📝 and read what others are sharing. It is wonderful how unique and personal the submissions are 😇
A scanned copy typewritten text</description></item><item><title>Typewriter Is Fine</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/typewriter-is-fine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 01:23:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/typewriter-is-fine/</guid><description>Today I realized my typewriter’s line spacing is absolutely fine. I just need to pull that line-by-line/continuous switch all the way to the right 🤦‍♂️</description></item><item><title>Journal</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/journal/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 20:48:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/journal/</guid><description>I spent the whole day working with my journal 📔 writing down thoughts helps to save ideas from being forgotten, and further reflection brings major discoveries ✨🔭</description></item><item><title>Don’t fight bad habits</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/dont-fight-bad-habits/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 18:11:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/dont-fight-bad-habits/</guid><description>You shouldn’t attempt eliminating bad habits because they are imperfect solutions to a problem you experience. You may even be grateful for them, as they helped you carry on until now… 😇 Once you came up with a better one, you won’t feel any resistance adopting new behaviour ✨ Or even solve the issue once and for all 💪</description></item><item><title>Oh, hi there</title><link>https://nikolai.kim/posts/oh-hi-there/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 17:49:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/posts/oh-hi-there/</guid><description>This would be my first post on Micro.blog platform 🥳 I had successfully wasted my trial period, but I can feel a great adventure ahead!
You take care ❤️</description></item><item><title/><link>https://nikolai.kim/pages/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nikolai.kim/pages/license/</guid><description>CC0 1.0 Universal CREATIVE COMMONS CORPORATION IS NOT A LAW FIRM AND DOES NOT PROVIDE LEGAL SERVICES. DISTRIBUTION OF THIS DOCUMENT DOES NOT CREATE AN ATTORNEY-CLIENT RELATIONSHIP. CREATIVE COMMONS PROVIDES THIS INFORMATION ON AN &amp;ldquo;AS-IS&amp;rdquo; BASIS. CREATIVE COMMONS MAKES NO WARRANTIES REGARDING THE USE OF THIS DOCUMENT OR THE INFORMATION OR WORKS PROVIDED HEREUNDER, AND DISCLAIMS LIABILITY FOR DAMAGES RESULTING FROM THE USE OF THIS DOCUMENT OR THE INFORMATION OR WORKS PROVIDED HEREUNDER.</description></item></channel></rss>